从前有位可爱的公主
Once upon a time there was a lovely princess.
但是她被可怕的魔法控制了
But she had an enchantment upon her of a fearful sort...
只有真爱的初吻才可以打破这魔法
which could only be broken by love's first kiss.
她被困在一个城堡里
She was locked away in a castle...
由一只喷火龙看守着
guarded by a terrible fire-breathing dragon.
有许多勇敢的骑士曾经想过把她从这可怕的监狱中救走
Many brave knights had attempted to free her from this dreadful prison,
但是 没有一个成功
but none prevailed.
她关在被喷火龙看守着的
She waited in the dragon's keep...
城堡里最高的房间里
in the highest room of the tallest tower...
等待着真爱的初吻
for her true love and true love's first kiss.
那是不会发生的
Like that's ever gonna happen.
Somebody once told me the world is gonna roll me
I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed
She was lookin' kind of dumb with her finger and her thumb
In the shape of an Lon her forehead
The years start comin ' and they don't stop comin'
怪物史瑞克
Didn't make sense not to live for fun
Your brain gets smart but your head gets dumb
So much to do So much to see
So what's wrong with takin' the backstreets
You'll never know if you don't go
You'll never shine if you don't glow
Hey, now You're an all-star
Get your game on, go play
Hey, now, you're a rockstar Get the show on, get paid
And all that glitters is gold
Only shootin' stars break the mould
It's a cool place and they say it gets colder
You'rebund led up now but wait till you get older
But the meteor men beg to differ
Judging by the hole in the satellite picture
The ice we skate is gettin' pretty thin
The water's getting warm so you might as well swim
My world's on fire How about yours
That's the way I like it and I'll never get bored
Hey, now, you're an all-star
Get your game on, go play
Hey, now, you're a rockstar Get the show on, get paid
And all that glitters is gold
Only shootin' stars break the mould
- 快 - 快
- Go! - Go!
Go. Go. Go.
Hey, now You're an all-star
Get your game on, go play
Hey, now, you're a rockstar Get the show on, get paid
And all that glitters is gold
Only shootin' stars break the mould
- 我想它在里面吧? - 好的 我们去吧!
- Think it's in there? - All right. Let's get it!
慢着! 你知道有什么后果吗?
Whoa. Hold on. Do you know what that thing can do to you?
嗯 它会把你的骨头当面包吃
Yeah, it'll grind your bones for its bread.
哈哈 实际上那会是一个巨人
Yes, well, actually, that would be agiant.
不过 青怪可能更糟糕
Now, ogres They're much worse.
它们会用你们的鲜皮做汤
They'll make a suit from your freshly peeled skin.
- 不 - 挖出你的心肝
- No! - They'll shave your liver.
用你们的眼睛榨果汁
Squeeze the jelly from your eyes!
- 这样吃吐司面包会很好味道! - 退后 退后 怪物!
- Actually, it's quite good on toast. - Back! Back, beast!
我警告你
Back! I warn ya!
好的
Right.
你们还不快走就没有机会了
This is the part where you run away.
滚
And stay out!
通缉 神话之物
Wanted. Fairy tale creatures.
好的 这个满了
All right. This one's full.
拉走
Take it away!
- 走 快点 快点 - 下一个
- Move it along. Come on! Get up! - Next!
给我 你飞行的日子要结束了
Give me that! Your flying days are over.
这是给女巫的20块银子 下一个!
That's 20 pieces of silver for the witch. Next!
- 起来 快点 - 20块
- Get up! Come on! - Twenty pieces.
在这里坐下
Sit down there!
安静!
Keep quiet!
笼子太小了
This cage is too small.
请不要让我进去 我不再固执了
Please don't turn me in. I'll never be stubborn again.
我会改的 给我多一次机会
I can change. Please! Give me another chance!
- 闭嘴 - 哦 - 下一个
- Oh, shut up. - Oh! - Next!
- 什么东西? - 这是一个小木偶
- What have you got? - This little wooden puppet.
我不是木偶 我是一个真正的男孩
I'm not a puppet. I'm a real boy.
5先令给这个疯狂的玩具
Five shillings for the possessed toy.
- 拿走 越远越好! - 老爸 别让他们这么做
- Take it away. - Father, please! Don't let them do this!
- 下一个 - 什么东西?
- Help me! - Next. What have you got?
- 呃 我有一个会说话的驴子
- Well, I've got a talking donkey.
好的 这个值10个先令 你可以证明一下吗?
Right. Well, that's good for ten shillings, if you can prove it.
好的 说吧 伙计
Oh, go ahead, little fella.
嗯?
Well?
哦 它只是有点紧张
Oh, oh, he's just He's just a little nervous.
它真的是一个话匣子 说?
He's really quite a chatterbox. Talk, you bone headed dolt
- 好了 我听够了 守卫! - 不 不 它能说话
- That's it. I've heard enough. Guards! - No, no, he talks!
我能说话 我爱说话
He does. I can talk. I love to talk.
我是你见过的最能说话的驴子
I'm the talkingest damn thing you ever saw.
- 把她带走 - 不 不要
- Get her out of my sight. - No, no!
我发誓 它能说话
I swear! Oh! He can talk!
嘿 我会飞!
Hey! I can fly!
- 它会飞 - 会飞!
- He can fly! - He can fly!
- 它说话了 - 对了 笨蛋
- He can talk! - Ha, ha! That's right, fool!
对 现在我是会飞会说话的驴子
Now I'm a flying, talking donkey.
你可能看过蝇子 而且是一个很大的蝇子
You might have seen a house fly, maybe even a super fly,
不过你肯定没有看过会飞的驴子
but I bet you ain't never seen a donkey fly.
哈哈
Ha, ha!
哦
Uh-oh.
捉住它
Seize him!
它要逃了
After him! He's getting away!
这边 转过来
Get him! This way! Turn!
是你 青怪
You there. Ogre!
什么事?
Aye?
奉弗瓜王之命 授权我逮捕你们两个
By the order of Lord Farquaad, I am authorized to place you both under arrest...
送到一个指定地
and transport you to a designated... resettlement facility.
是吗? 你们是什么军队?
Oh, really? You and what army?
我可以跟你说话吗?
Can I say something to you?
听着 你的确有些本领 了不起!
Listen, you was really, really somethin' back there. Incredible!
你在跟我说话吗?
Are you talkin' to me? Whoa!
是的 我在跟你说话 你刚才在侍卫那里真的很厉害
Yes, I was talkin' to you. Can I tell you that you was great back there? Those guards!
那些侍卫以为他们很棒 然后你一出现 砰!
They thought they was all of that. Then you showed up, and bam!
都跑光了
They was trippin' over themselves like babes in the woods.
看到这样确实使我感觉很好
That really made me feel good to see that.
- 很棒 真的 - 朋友 自由是很好的
- Oh, that's great. Really. - Man, it's good to be free.
现在跟你的朋友去庆祝你的自由 好吗?
Now, why don't you go celebrate your freedom with your own friends? Hmm?
但是 我没有朋友
But, uh, I don't have any friends.
我也不会自己一个人出去
And I'm not goin' out there by myself.
嘿 等等 我有一个很好的提议 我跟你一起
Hey, wait a minute! I got a great idea! I'll stick with you.
你是一个令人惧怕青怪
You're a mean, green, fightin' machine.
我们一起会吓跑经过我们的人
Together we'll scare the spit out of anybody that crosses us.
噢 真吓人
Oh, wow! That was really scary.
这很可怕 如果这不起作用 你的呼吸会起作用的
If you don't mind me sayin if that don't work, your breath certainly will get the job done,
你需要些口香糖 你喘气太臭了!
'cause you definitely need some Tic Tacs or something, 'cause your breath stinks!
你几乎把我的鼻毛都烧着了
You almost burned the hair outta my nose,
就像那次
just like the time
烂草莓 我那天放了很多屁
Then I ate some rotten berries. I had strong gases eking out ofmy butt that day.
你为什么跟着我?
Why are you following me?
我告诉你为什么
I'll tell you why.
'Cause I'm all alone
There's no one here beside me
My problems have all gone
There's no one to deride me
But you gotta have friends
别唱了!
Stop singing!
怪不得你没有朋友
It's no wonder you don't have any friends.
噢 只有真正的朋友才会这么诚实
Wow. Only a true friend would be that truly honest.
听着 驴子 看看我 我是谁?
Listen, little donkey. Take a look at me. What am I?
嗯
Uh
- 真高? - 不! 我是个妖怪
- Really tall? - No! I'm an ogre.
你想一下 拿着你的火把和草杈!
You know. Grab your torch and pitchforks.
这不让你烦恼吗?
Doesn't that bother you?
不
Nope.
- 真的? - 真的 真的
- Really? - Really, really.
-噢 - 我喜欢你 你叫什么?
- Oh. - Man, I like you. What's your name?
史瑞克
Uh, Shrek.
史瑞克? 知道我喜欢你什么?
Shrek? Well, you know what I like about you, Shrek?
我不在乎别人怎么看我
You got that kind of I don't care what nobody thinks of me thing.
我喜欢这个 我敬佩这个 史瑞克
I like that. I respect that, Shrek. You all right.
瞧那里! 谁想住在那里?
Whoo! Look at that. Who'd want to live in a place like that?
那是我的家
That would be my home.
很好! 很漂亮!
Oh! And it is lovely! Just beautiful.
你是个相当不错的装饰设计家 在预算有限的情况下 你所干的令人惊叹!
You are quite a decorator. It's amazing what you've done with such a modest budget.
我喜欢那块石头 那是块不错的石头
I like that boulder. That is a nice boulder.
我猜想你不常有客人
I guess you don't entertain much, do you?
我喜欢一个人呆着
I like my privacy.
我也是一样 这是我们的另一个共同点
You know, I do too. That's another thing we have in common.
我讨厌有人来
Like, I hate it when you got somebody in your face.
来了就不肯走 尴尬的沉默
You're trying to give them a hint, and they won't leave. There's that awkward silence.
- 我跟你住可以吗? - 什么?
- Can I stay with you? - Uh, what?
让我跟你一起住好吗?
Can I stay with you, please?
- 当然! -真的?
- Of course! - Really?
- 不! - 我不想回去!
- No. - Please! I don't wanna go back there!
你不知道怪物的生活是什么样的 也许你知道
You don't know what it's like to be considered a freak. Well, may be you do.
这就是为什么我们要在一起 让我留下吧!
But that's why we gotta stick together. You gotta let me stay!
- 求求你! - 好的
- Please! Please! - Okay! Okay!
- 但只能呆一晚上 - 谢谢!
- But one night only. - Ah! Thank you!
- 你干什么 不 不 - 这将会很有趣!
- What are you No! No! - This is gonna be fun!
我们晚点儿睡 一起讲故事
We can stay up late, swappin' manly stories,
早上我做华夫饼
and in the mornin' I'm makin' waffles.
- 哦 - 我在哪里睡?
- Oh! - Where do, uh, I sleep?
外头!
Outside!
哇 那很酷
Oh, well, I guess that's cool.
我的意思是我不了解你 你也不了解我
I mean, I don't know you, and you don't know me,
因此我想外头最好
so I guess outside is best, you know.
我出去了
Here I go.
晚安
Good night.
我确实喜欢在外头 我是驴子生来就喜欢外头
I mean, I do like the outdoors. I'm a donkey. I was born outside.
只有我一个人在外头
I'll just be sitting by myself outside, I guess, you know.
一个人 在外头
By myself, outside.
只有我一个人 这里除了我没有别人
I'm all alone There's no one here beside me
我不是告诉你呆在外头吗?
I thought I told you to stay outside.
我是在外头
I am outside.
老头 这比农场差远了 不过还有什么办法呢?
Well, gents, it's a farcry from the farm, but what choice do we have?
这不是家 但还算不错
It's not home, but it'll do just fine.
多好的床
What a lovely bed.
- 抓到了 - 我找到了些奶酪
- Got ya. - I found some cheese.
- 哦 - 真恶心!
- Ow! - Biah! Awful stuff.
- 是你吗 戈德? - 你怎么知道是我?
- Is that you, Gorder? - How did you know?
够了! 你在我的房子里干嘛?
Enough! What are you doing in my house?
嘿
Hey!
不 不 不!
Oh, no, no, no.
- 死女人不能放在桌子上 - 但床已经被占了!
- Dead broad off the table. - Where are we supposed to put her? The bed's taken.
啊?
Huh?
什么?
What?
我住在沼泽地里 我出告示 我 我是个可怕的妖怪!
I live in a swamp. I put up signs. I'm a terrifying ogre!
我怎么才能有点儿隐私呢?
What do I have to do to get a little privacy?
- 啊! - 不
- Aah! - Oh, no.
哦 不要
Oh, no.
不 不!
No! No!
什么?
What?
- 停下 - 别推
- Quit it. - Don't push.
你们在我的沼泽地里干什么?
What are you doing in my swamp?
沼泽 沼泽 沼泽
Swamp! Swamp! Swamp!
哦 亲爱的
Oh, dear!
哇
Whoa!
好 出去 你们都出去 都走开!
All right, get out of here. All of you, move it!
快点儿 快!
Come on! Let's go! Hapaya! Hapaya! Hey!
- 快点儿 快! - 不
- Quickly. Come on! - No, no!
不是那里 不是那里
No, no. Not there. Not there.
哦
Oh!
别看我 我没有邀请他们
Hey, don't look at me. I didn't invite them.
天哪 没人邀请我们
Oh, gosh, no one invited us.
- 什么? - 我们被迫来到这里
- What? - We were forced to come here.
- 谁强迫你们? - 弗瓜王
- By who? - Lord Farquaad.
他连吹带唬 签署了搬迁布告
He huffed und he puffed und he... signed an eviction notice.
好的
All right.
听着 有人知道弗瓜王现在在哪里吗?
Who knows where this Farquaad guy is?
我知道他在哪里
Oh, I do. I know where he is.
还有人知道在哪里能找到他吗?
Does anyone else know where to find him?
- 没人知道? - 我知道!
- Any one at all? - Me! Me!
- 谁知道? - 选择我!
- Anyone? - Oh! Oh, pick me!
我知道! 我知道! 我!
Oh, I know! I know! Me, me!
好
Okay, fine.
注意 所有的神话故事人物
Attention, all fairy tale things.
别再享受了 欢迎已经正式结束了
Do not get comfortable. Your welcome is officially worn out.
实际上 我马上就要去见弗瓜王这个家伙
In fact, I'm gonna see this guy Farquaad right now...
把你们从我的地里赶走 哪来哪去!
and get you all off my land and back where you came from!
你!
Oh! You!
你跟我来
You're comin' with me.
这正是我喜欢听到的
All right, that's what I like to hear, man.
史瑞克和驴子两个朋友一起去冒大险
Shrek and Donkey, two stalwart friends, off on a whirlwind big-city adventure.
我喜欢
I love it!
- 又上路了史瑞克 跟我唱歌 - 噢 不
- On the road again Sing it with me, Shrek. - Hey. Oh, oh!
我急不可待要上路了
I can't wait to get on the road again
我刚才没说什么
What did I say about singing?
- 我可以吹口哨儿吗? - 不
- Can I whistle? - No.
- 哼歌吗? - 行 哼吧
- Can I hum it? - All right, hum it.
够了 他要开口了
That's enough. He's ready to talk.
跑 跑 赶快跑
Run, run, run, as fast as you can.
你抓不到我 我是个姜饼人!
You can't catch me. I'm the ginger bread man!
- 你是个魔鬼 - 我不是 你是
- You're a monster. - I'm not the monster here. You are.
你和其他的神话故事垃圾毒坏了我完美的世界
You and the rest of that fairy tale trash, poisoning my perfect world.
他们都到哪里去了?
Now, tell me! Where are the others?
吃我!
Eat me!
我设法公平地对待你们这些东西
I've tried to be fair to you creatures.
现在 我的耐心消失了! 告诉我 不然
Now my patience has reached its end! Tell me or I'll
不 别动我的糖浆扣子!
No, no, not the buttons. Not my gumdrop buttons.
谁把他们藏起来了?
All right then. Who's hiding them?
好 我告诉你 你知道松饼人吗?
Okay, I'll tell you. Doyou know the muffin man?
- 松饼人? - 松饼人
- The muffin man? - The muffin man.
对 我知道松饼人 她住在特鲁里街?
Yes, I know the muffin man, who lives on Drury Lane?
她跟松饼人结婚了
Well, she's married to the muffin man.
- 松饼人? - 松饼人!
- The muffin man? - The muffin man!
她跟松饼人结婚了
She's married to the muffin man.
主人! 我们找到了?
My lord! We found it.
你还等什么? 把它拿进来
Then what are you waiting for? Bring it in.
哦
Oh!
- 魔镜 - 别告诉他!
- Magic mirror - Don't tell him anything!
别!
No!
晚安
Evening.
镜子 镜子 墙上的镜子
Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
这不是最完美的王国吗?
Is this not the most perfect kingdom of them all?
严格地讲你不是国王
Well, technically you're not a king.
西龙涅斯
Uh, Thelonius.
- 你说什么? - 我说你还不是国王
- You were saying? - What I mean is, you're not a king yet.
但你可以成为国王 你只要和公主结婚就行了
But you can become one. All you have to do is marry a princess.
接着说
Go on.
那么 放松坐下吧 我的主人
So,just sit back and relax, my lord,
因为你就要会见当今最合格的未婚女子了
because it's time for you to meet today's eligible bachelorettes.
她们来了!
And here they are!
一号倍受精神折磨 她被关在遥远的王国
Bachelorette numberone is a mentally abused shut-in from a kingdom far, far away.
她喜欢吃寿司和洗热水浴
She likes sushi and hot tubbing anytime.
她的爱好还包括为她的两个坏姐姐清理卫生
Herhobbies include cooking and cleaning for her two evilsisters.
请大家欢迎灰姑娘!
Please welcome Cinderella.
二号是位身穿斗篷的姑娘 她来自奇妙的国土
Bachelorett enumber two is a cape-wearinggirl from the land of fancy.
她与七个男人一起生活 但她很不简单
Although she lives with seven other men, she's not easy.
吻她冰凉的嘴唇 看看她的激情有多么强烈
Just kiss her dead, frozen lips and find out whata live wire she is.
快来为白雪公主鼓掌吧!
Come on. Give it up for Snow White!
最后 但当然不是最差的
And last, but certainly not least,
一位来自火山岩浆围绕城堡
bachelorette number three is a fieryred head...
被龙看守的红发姑娘
from a dragon-guardedcastle surrounded by hotboiling lava!
但别因此而灰心
But don't let that cool you off.
她是个上了膛的手枪 喜欢喝皮钠-可拉达
She's a loaded pistol who like spina coladas and getting caught in the rain.
你去救她 菲奥纳公主
Yours for the rescuing, Princess Fiona!
是一号?
So will it be bachelorette number one,
还是三号?
bachelorette number two or bachelorette number three?
- 二号! - 三号! 三号!
- Two! Two! - Three! Three!
- Two! Two! - Three!
三? 一? 三?
Three? One? Three?
选三号吧 主人!
Three! Pick number three, my lord!
好 好 三号!
Okay, okay, uh, number three!
弗瓜王 你挑选了菲奥纳公主
Lord Farquaad, you've chosen Princess Fiona.
If you like pina coladas
菲奥纳公主
Princess Fiona.
她是十全十美的
She's perfect.
我只想找一个
All I have to do is just find someone
我应该说一下儿晚上的事
But I probably should mention the little thing that happens at night.
- 我会跟她结婚的 - 日落后
- I'll do it. - Yes, but after sunset
安静! 我要让菲奥纳公主成为王后
Silence! I will make this Princess Fiona my queen,
杜洛克最终将有一个十全十美的国王
and DuLoc will finally have the perfect king!
队长 集合你最好的士兵
Captain, assemble your finest men.
我们就要举行比武大会了
We're going to have a tournament.
就在那里 那是杜洛克
But that's it. That's it right there. That's DuLoc.
我说过我会找到的
I told ya I'd find it.
那么 那一定是弗瓜王的城堡了
So, that must be Lord Farquaad's castle.
就是那里
Uh-huh. That's the place.
你看他是不是在弥补什么?
Do you think maybe he's compensating for something?
等等! 等一下儿 史瑞克
Hey, wait. Wait up, Shrek.
快点儿 宝贝儿 我们晚了
Hurry, darling. We're late. Hurry.
嘿
Hey, you!
等等 我不会吃掉你的
Wait a second. Look, I'm not gonna eat ya.
我只是我只
I just I just
很安静
It's quiet.
太安静了
Too quiet.
- 人都到哪里去了? - 你看看这个!
- Where is everybody? - Hey, look at this!
Welcome to DuLoc such a perfect town
Here we have some rules Let us lay them down
Don't make waves stay in line and we'll get along fine
DuLoc is a perfect place
Please keep off of the grass Shine your shoes wipe yourface
DuLoc is DuLoc is
DuLoc is a perfect
Place
我们再来一遍!
Wow! Let's do that again!
不 不 不 不!
No. No. No, no, no! No.
勇敢的骑士
Brave knights.
你们是世界上最优秀 最聪明的人
You are the best and brightest in all the land.
今天 你们中的一个将证明
Today one of you shall prove himself
你想挨揍?
All right. You're going the right way for a smacked bottom.
对不起
Sorry about that.
冠军将得到荣誉 不 特权
That champion shall have the honour no, no the privilege...
去从龙严密的看守中
to go forth and rescue the lovely Princess Fiona...
救出可爱的菲奥纳公主
from the fiery keep oft he dragon.
如果由于什么原因冠军没有成功
If for any reason the winner is unsuccessful,
亚军将接着去完成
the first runner-up will take his place...
如此类推
and so on and so forth.
你们中间有些人可能会死 但这是我愿意做出的牺牲
Some of you may die, but it's a sacrifice I am willing to make.
比武现在开始!
Let the tournament begin!
哦
Oh!
那是什么?
What is that?
- 真丑死人了! - 这可不怎么样
- It's hideous! - Ah, that's not very nice.
- 不过是头驴子- 嗯?
- It's just a donkey. - Huh?
骑士们 新计划!
Indeed. Knights, new plan!
杀死那个妖怪的人将被授予冠军! 进攻!
The one who kills the ogre will be named champion! Have at him!
- 抓住他! - 现在 快! 等等
- Gethim! - Oh, hey! Now come on! Hang on now.
去! 抓住他!
Go ahead! Get him!
我们可以喝酒解决吗?
Can't wejust settle this over a pint?
杀死这个野兽!
Kill the beast!
不? 那么 好吧
No? All right then.
来吧!
Come on!
I don't give a damn about my reputation
You're living in the past It's a new generation
A girl can do what she wants to do
And that's what I'm gonna do
And I don't give a damn about my bad reputation
Oh no no no no no Not me
- 我 我 - 嘿 史瑞克 让我来! 让我来!
- Me, me, me - Hey, Shrek, tag me! Tag me!
And I don't give a damn about my reputation
Never said I wanted to improve my station
Ah!
And I'm always feelin'good when I'm having fun
And I don't have to please no one
给他坐电椅!
The chair! Give him the chair!
And I don't give a damn about my bad reputation
Oh no no no no no Not me
Me me me
Oh no no no no
Not me not me
Not me
哦 啊啊
Oh, yeah! Ah! Ah!
谢谢! 十分感谢!
Thank you! Thank you very much!
我一直呆到周四 尝尝牛肉!
I'm here till Thursday. Try the veal! Ha, ha!
我可以下命令吗 主人?
Shall I give the order, sir?
不 我有个更好的主意
No, I have a better idea.
杜洛克的人们 他就是我们的冠军!
People of DuLoc, I give you our champion!
- 什么? - 祝贺你 青怪
- What? - Congratulations, ogre.
你赢得了从事一个伟大 高尚的任务荣誉
You've won the honour of embarking on a great and noble quest.
任务? 我的任务就是要寻求归还我的沼泽地
Quest? I'm already on a quest, a quest to get my swamp back.
- 你的沼泽地? - 对 我的沼泽地!
- Your swamp? - Yeah, my swamp!
你把那些家伙扔在那里!
Where you dumped those fairy tale creatures!
的确
Indeed.
是的 妖怪 我们做个交易
All right, ogre, I'll make you a deal.
你为我完成任务 我就把沼泽地还给你
Go on this quest for me, and I'll give you your swamp back.
恢复原状?
Exactly the way it was?
恢复到粘泥覆盖的原始模样
Down to the last slime-covered toad stool.
- 那些擅自占据者呢? - 全部搬走
- And the squatters? - As good as gone.
什么样的任务?
What kind of quest?
你要去跟龙作战
Let me get this straight. You're gonna go fight a dragon...
救出公主 然后回到沼泽地去
and rescue a princess just so Farquaad will give you back a swamp...
你现在没有沼泽地了 因为弗瓜王塞了些怪物进去
which you only don't have because he filled it full of freaks in the first place.
- 这不对吗? - 也许驴子不会讲话是有道理的
- Is that about right? - Maybe there's a good reason donkeys shouldn't talk.
你为什么不把你的魔力都用在他身上?
I don't get it. Why don't you just pull some of that ogre stuffon him?
包围他的堡垒
Throttle him, lay siege to his fortress,
碾碎他的骨头夹面包吃 妖怪所有的本事
grind his bones to make your bread, the whole ogre trip.
我知道
Oh, I know what.
也许我可以砍掉全村人的头
Maybe I could have decapitated an entire village...
把他们挂在长矛上
and put their heads on a pike,
拿把刀 割开他们的脾 喝他们的脾液
gotten a knife, cut open their spleen and drink their fluids.
你看怎么样?
Does that sound good to you?
不 真的 不怎么样
Uh, no, not really, no.
告诉你 妖怪比你想像的复杂
For your information, there's a lot more to ogres than people think.
- 举个例子 - 例子?
- Example? - Example?
- 好妖怪就像洋葱 - 它们辣臭?
- Okay, um, ogres are like onions. - They stink?
- 不 - 让你流泪? - 不!
- Yes No! - They make you cry? - No!
你把它们放在阳光下 它们都会变黄?
You leave them out in the sun, they get all brown, start sproutin' little white hairs.
是层!
No! Layers!
洋葱有很多多层
Onions have layers.
妖怪多层! 洋葱多层
Ogres have layers! Onions have layers.
你明白吗? 我们都有好多层
You get it? We both have layers.
你们都有好多层
Oh, you both have layers. Oh.
可并不是人人都喜欢洋葱
You know, not everybody likes onions.
蛋糕! 大家都喜欢蛋糕!
Cake! Everybody loves cakes! Cakes have layers.
我不管大家喜欢什么
I don't care... what everyone likes.
妖怪不像蛋糕
Ogres are not like cakes.
你知道大家还喜欢什么? 冻糕
You know what else everybody likes? Parfaits.
你试过问别人: 吃冻糕
Have you ever met a person, you say, Let's get some parfait,
他回答: 不 我不喜欢冻糕?
they say, No, I don't like no parfait?
- 冻糕味道好极了 - 没有!
- Parfaits are delicious. - No!
你这个愚蠢讨厌的驴子
You dense, irritating, miniature beast of burden!
妖怪像洋葱!行了吧
Ogres are like onions! End of story.
再见 回头见
Bye-bye. See ya later.
冻糕也许是这个星球上最可口的东西
Parfaits may be the most delicious thing on the whole damn planet.
我想我宁愿听你哼歌
You know, I think I preferred your humming.
你有餐巾纸吗? 我这里一塌糊涂
Do you have a tissue or something? I'm makinga mess.
冻糕这个词让我流口水了
Just the word parfait make me start slobbering.
I'm on my way from misery to happiness today
Uh-huh uh-huh Uh-huh uh-huh
And everything that you receive up yonder
Is what you give to me the day I wander
I'm on my way
史瑞克! 是你干的吗?
Ooh! Shrek! Did you do that?
你放屁之前得通知一声
You gotta warn somebody before you just crack one off. My mouth was open.
相信我 驴子如果是我 你早就薰死了
Believe me, Donkey, if it was me, you'd be dead.
是硫磺石
It's brimstone.
- 我们一定快到了 - 对 硫磺石
- We must be getting close. - Yeah, right, brimstone.
别告诉我硫磺石 我知道我闻到了什么 不可能是硫磺石
Don't be talking about it's the brimstone. I know what I smell. It wasn't no brimstone.
也没有什么石头
It didn't come off no stone neither.
确实 够大的了 但看一下位置
Sure, it's big enough, but look at the location.
史瑞克? 记得你说过妖怪有好多层吗?
Uh, Shrek? Uh, remember when you said ogres have layers?
没错
Oh, aye.
我有点儿事要坦白
Well, I have a bit ofa confession to make.
驴子没有好多层 我们的恐惧都表现在袖子上
Donkeys don't have layers. We wear our fear right out there on our sleeves.
- 等等! 驴子没有袖子 - 你明白我的意思
- Wait a second. Donkeys don't have sleeves. - You know what I mean.
你不能对我说你怕高
You can't tell me you're afraid of heights.
在沸腾岩浆湖摇晃的桥上走我不舒服
I'm just a little uncomfortable about being on a rickety bridge over a boiling lake of lava!
别怕 驴子我就在你身边
Come on, Donkey. I'm right here beside ya, okay?
帮助和鼓励你
For emotional support,
我们一起来通过 一次迈一婴儿小步
we'll just tackle this thing together one little baby step at a time.
- 真的? - 真的 真的
- Really? - Really, really.
- 这样我感觉好多了 - 往前走
- Okay, that makes me feel so much better. - Just keep moving.
- 别往下看 - 别往下看 别往下看
- And don't look down. - Okay, don't look down. Don't look down.
别往下看 往前走 别往下看
Don't look down. Keep on moving. Don't look down.
史瑞克! 我在往下看!
Shrek! I'm lookin' down!
我过不去了! 请放了我吧!
Oh, God, I can't do this! Just let me off, please!
- 你已经走了一半了! - 我知道那部分安全!
- But you're already halfway. - But I know that halfis safe!
好 我没有时间 你回去吧
Okay, fine. I don't have time for this. You go back.
- 史瑞克! - 等等!
- Shrek, no! Wait! -Just, Donkey
- 我们交换一下儿位置 - 别这样!
- Let's have a dance then, shall we? - Don't do that!
对不起 别哪样?
Oh, I'm sorry. Do what?
- 这样? - 对 那样
- Oh, this? - Yes, that!
怎么了? 就这样 好
Yes? Yes, do it. Okay.
不 史瑞克
No, Shrek!
- 不! 停下! - 你说就这样! 我在这样做啊
- No! Stop it! - You said do it! I'm doin' it.
史瑞克 我要死了 我要死了
I'm gonna die. I'm gonna die. Shrek, I'm gonna die.
哦
Oh!
这就行了 驴子这就行了
That'll do, Donkey. That'll do.
酷
Cool.
那么喷火的家伙在哪里?
So where is this fire breathing pain in the neck anyway?
在里面 等我们来救她
Inside, waiting for us to rescue her.
我说的是那条龙 史瑞克
I was talkin' about the dragon, Shrek.
你怕吗?
You afraid?
不怕 但
No, but Shh.
嗯 我也不怕
Oh, good. Me neither.
害怕并不是过错
'Cause there's nothin' wrong with bein' afraid.
害怕是对陌生环境的敏感反应
Fear's a sensible response to an unfamiliar situation.
陌生的危险环境
Unfamiliar dangerous situation, I might add.
有一条喷火的龙
With a dragon that breathes fire and eats knights and breathes fire,
害怕并不意味着你是胆小鬼
it sure doesn't mean you're a coward if you're a little scared.
我确信史瑞克不是胆小鬼
I sure as heck ain't no coward. I know that.
驴子 两件事 好吗?
Donkey, two things, okay?
闭 嘴
Shut... up.
闭嘴 去看看能不能找到楼梯
Now go over there and see if you can find any stairs.
楼梯? 我以为我们在找公主
Stairs? I thought we was lookin' for the princess.
她在楼上在最高塔内最高的房间里
The princess will be up the stairs in the highest room in the tallest tower.
- 你怎么知道她在那里? - 我从书上看到的
- What makes you think she'll be there? - I read it in a book once.
酷 你对付龙 我来找楼梯
Cool. You handle the dragon. I'll handle the stairs.
等我找到楼梯 我也要抽它们的屁股
I'll find those stairs. I'll whip their butt too.
它们并不知道该去哪里
Those stairs won't know which way they're goin'.
我要走难走的路
I'm gonna take drastic steps.
别打扰我 我是爬楼梯老手
Kick it to the kerb. Don't mess with me. I'm the stair master.
我已经征服楼梯了 踏上一步就没有问题了
I've mastered the stairs. I wish I had a step right here. I'd step all over it.
至少我们知道公主在哪里 但哪里
Well, at least we know where the princess is, but where's the
喷火龙!
Dragon!
驴子当心!
Donkey, look out!
抓住你了!
Got ya!
哇 哇 哇
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
哦 啊啊
Oh! Aah! Aah!
哦 不 不
No. Oh, no. No!
你的牙齿真大
Oh, what large teeth you have.
我是说 闪亮的牙齿 你也许经常听人这么夸奖
I mean, white, sparkling teeth. I know you probably hear this all the time from your food,
但你一定漂白了 因为你的笑很耀眼
but you must bleach, 'cause that is one dazzling smile you got there.
我闻到了 是薄荷味吗?
Do I detect a hint of minty freshness?
你知道吗? 你是条雌龙!
And you know what else? You're You're a girl dragon!
当然! 我是说 当然你是雌龙
Oh, sure! I mean, of course you're a girl dragon.
你散发着女性的美
You're just reeking of feminine beauty.
你怎么了? 眼里掉进东西了?
What's the matter with you? You got something in your eye?
噢
Ooh. Oh. Oh.
我真的愿意留下 但
Man, I'd really love to stay, but, you know, I'm, uh
我有气喘病如果你吐烟圈我会受不了的
I'm an asthmatic, and I don't know if it'd work out if you're gonna blow smoke rings.
史瑞克!
Shrek!
不 史瑞克! 史瑞克!
No! Shrek! Shrek!
史瑞克
Shrek!
哦 哦
Oh! Oh!
- 醒醒! - 什么?
- Wake up! - What?
你是菲奥纳公主吗?
Areyou Princess Fiona?
是 我在等待一个勇敢的骑士来救我
I am, awaiting a knight so bold as to rescue me.
很好 我们走吧!
Oh, that's nice. Now let's go!
等等 骑士先生
But wait, Sir Knight.
这是我们第一次见面
This being our first meeting.
这不该是一个非常浪漫的时刻吗?
Should it not be a wonderful, romantic moment?
- 是 对不起 女士没时间 - 你在干什么?
- Yeah, sorry, lady. There's no time. - Hey, wait. What are you doing?
你应该抱起我
You should sweep me off my feet...
冲出远处的窗户 落在你勇敢的马上
out yonder window and down a rope onto your valiant steed.
你有很多时间计划这些 是不是?
You've had a lot of time to plan this, haven't you?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
但我们得品尝这个时刻!
But we have to savour this moment!
你该给我背段壮丽的诗
You could recite an epic poem for me.
叙事史诗? 14行诗!
A ballad? A sonnet!
- 5行打油诗? 或是别的! - 我并不这样认为
- A limerick? Or something! - I don't think so.
至少我该知道英雄的名字吧?
Can I at least know the name of my champion?
我叫史瑞克
Um, Shrek.
史瑞克先生
Sir Shrek.
我祈求你把这个手帕当作我感谢的象征
I pray that you take this favour as a token of my gratitude.
谢谢
Thanks!
你没有杀死龙?
You didn't slay the dragon?
- 这在我们的计划内 - 来!
- It's on my to do list. - Now come on!
但不该这样!
But this isn't right!
你应该像其他骑士一样 在他们被烧死前 冲锋陷阵 挥剑拔刀
You were meant to charge in, sword drawn, banner flying.
所有的骑士都应该这样
That's what all the other knights did.
在他们被烧成焦炭之前对吧?
Yeah, right before they burst into flame.
这不是问题所在
That's not the point. Oh!
你去哪里? 出口在那边儿
Wait. Where are you going? The exit's over there.
我要救我的驴子
Well, I have to save my ass.
你是什么骑士?
What kind of knight are you?
独一无二的骑士
One of a kind.
慢点儿 慢点儿 宝贝儿
Slowdown. Slowdown, baby, please.
时间久了才能全面了解一个人
I believe it's healthy to get to know someone over a long period of time.
就叫我老古板吧
Just call me old fashioned.
我不想仓促拥有肉体关系
I don't want to rush into a physical relationship.
我感情上还没有投入这
I'm not emotionally ready for a commitment of, uh, this
伟大是我要找的字
Magnitude really is the word I'm looking for.
伟大 这是不想要的肉体关系
Magnitude Hey, that is unwanted physical contact.
你在干什么?
Hey, what are you doing?
让我们回头一步一步地来
Okay, okay. Let's just back up a little and take this one step at a time.
我们真的应该先做个朋友或者笔友
We really should get to know each other first as friend sorpenpals.
我经常在路上旅行 但我喜欢接收明信片
I'm on theroada lot, but I just love receiving cards
我确实想留下 但
I'd really love to stay, but
别这样! 这是我私人的尾巴
Don't do that! That's my tail! That's my personal tail.
你要去掉? 你要用它做什么?
You're gonna tear it off. I don't give permission What are you gonna do with that?
现在! 不行 不!
Hey, now. No way. No! No!
不 不 不 不
No, no! No. No, no, no! No! Oh!
- 嗨 公主! - 它会说话!
- Hi, Princess! - It talks!
对 让他闭嘴得用窍门
Yeah, it's getting him to shut up that's the trick.
哦
Oh!
好 你们俩 朝出口前进!
Okay, you two, head for the exit!
我来对付龙
I'll take care of the dragon.
快跑
Run!
你成功了! 你救了我!
You did it!
真令人惊叹 你
You rescued me! You're amazing. You're
你太伟大了 你是
You're wonderful. You're...
我得承认 有点儿怪
a little unorthodox I'll admit.
但你的行为伟大 心底纯洁
But thy deed is great, and thine heart is pure.
我将永远感激你
I am eternally in your debt.
没有高贵的马 哪里有勇敢的骑士?
And where would a brave knight be without his noble steed?
我希望你听到了这些话 她说我是高贵的马!
I hope you heard that. She called me a noble steed. She think I'm a steed.
战斗打赢了
The battle is won.
你可以摘掉头盔了 好骑士先生
You may remove your helmet, good Sir Knight.
- 不? - 为什么不?
- Uh, no. - Why not?
我的头发被压扁了
I have helmet hair.
求你 我想看看救我人的脸
Please. I would'st look upon the face of my rescuer.
不 不 你不想
No, no, you wouldn't 'st.
可你怎么吻我?
But how will you kiss me?
什么? 这不在工作的要求里
What? That wasn't in the job description.
也许是个奖赏
Maybe it's a perk.
不 是命运 你一定要知道是怎么回事
No, it's destiny. Oh, you must know how it goes.
一个被关在塔楼里 由龙看守的公主
A princess locked in a tower and be set by a dragon...
被一个勇敢的骑士搭救了
is rescued by a brave knight,
然后他们分享了真爱的第一个吻
and then they share true love's first kiss.
和史瑞克? 你想等等
Hmm? With Shrek? You think Wait.
你以为他是你的真爱?
Wait. You think that Shrek is your true love?
是啊!
Well, yes.
你以为史瑞克是你的真爱!?
You think Shrek is your true love!
这有什么好笑的?
What is so funny?
我不是你喜欢的类型
Let's just say I'm not your type, okay?
你是 你救了我
Of course, you are. You're my rescuer.
现在 摘掉你的头盔
Now Now remove your helmet.
这不是个好主意
Look. I really don't think this is a good idea.
- 就把头盔摘掉 - 不
- Just take off the helmet. - I'm not going to.
- 摘掉 现在! - 不!
- Take it off. - No!
- 现在! - 好!
- Now! - Okay!
别发火 听从你的命令 阁下
Easy. As you command, Your Highness.
你 你是个青怪
You You're an ogre.
你以为我像王子一样漂亮?
Oh, you were expecting Prince Charming.
嗯 对 是这样的
Well, yes, actually.
不 都搞错了
Oh, no. This is all wrong.
你不应该是个青怪
You're not supposed to be an ogre.
公主 我是被弗瓜王派来救你的
Princess, I was sent to rescue you by Lord Farquaad, okay?
是他想跟你结婚
He's the one who wants to marry you.
那他为什么不来救我?
Then why didn't he come rescue me?
好问题 到那里后你去问他
Good question. You should ask him that when we get there.
但我该被真爱的人搭救
But I have to be rescued by my true love,
而不是被妖怪和他的宠物搭救
not by some ogre and his his pet.
再也不是高贵的马了
So much for noble steed.
你使我的工作更麻烦了
You're not making my job any easier.
对不起 你的工作不是我的问题
I'm sorry, but your job is not my problem.
你去告诉弗瓜王 如果他想体面地救我
You can tell Lord Farquaad that if he wants to rescue me properly,
我就在这里等他
I'll be waiting for him right here.
我不是个送信的 我是个送货的
Hey! I'm no one's messenger boy, all right? I'm a delivery boy.
你不敢
You wouldn't dare.
- 把我放下! - 你来吗 驴子?
- Put me down! - Ya comin', Donkey?
我就在你后面
I'm right behind ya.
放下我 不然你将自食其果!
Put me down, or you will suffer the consequences!
这太没有尊严了! 放下我!
This is not dignified! Put me down!
现在又有个问题
Okay, so here's another question.
有个女人她喜欢你 但你不喜欢她
Say there's a woman that digs you, right, but you don't really like her that way.
怎么才能容易地摆脱她而不让她受伤害呢?
How do you let her down real easy so her feelings aren't hurt,
而你也不会她所伤害或吃掉?
butyou don't get burned to a crisp and eaten?
就告诉她 她不是你真爱的人
You just tell her she's not your true love.
当发现了真爱时 每个人都明白会
Everyone knowest what happens when you find your
嘿
Hey!
越早赶到杜洛克越好
The soonerwe get to DuLoc the better.
你会喜欢那里的 那里很美丽!
You're gonna love it there, Princess. It's beautiful!
我的未婚夫弗瓜王怎么样? 他长得什么样?
And what of my groom to be? Lord Farquaad? What's he like?
我这样来说吧 公主
Let me put it this way, Princess.
像弗瓜王那样的人很少
Men of Farquaad's stature are in short supply.
我不知道 有人很少瞧见他
I don't know. There are those who think little of him.
停下 你俩都停下
Stop it. Stop it, both of you.
你们是在嫉妒 你们没法跟弗瓜王比
You're just jealous you can never measure up to a great ruler like Lord Farquaad.
对 也许你说得对 公主
Yeah, well, maybe you're right, Princess.
但明天见到他时 你最好亲自量量他
But I'll let you do the measuring when you see him tomorrow.
明天? 要等那么久啊?
Tomorrow? It'll take that long?
- 我们停下露营吧? - 不 那会更久
- Shouldn't we stop to make camp? - No, that'll take longer.
- 我们接着走吧 - 但树林里可能有强盗
- We can keep going. - But there's robbers in the woods.
停下! 露营现在听起来不错!
Whoa! Time out, Shrek! Camping's starting to sound good.
我比这个森林里任何的东西都更可怕
Hey, come on. I'm scarier than anything we're going to see in this forest.
我要找个地方露营!
I need to find somewhere to camp now!
- 哎!过来 - 史瑞克 我们可以找个更好的地方
- Hey! Over here. - Shrek, we can do better than that.
我认为这对一位公主并不合适
I don't think this is fit for a princess.
不 不 太完美了 它只不过需要一点家的气氛
No, no, it's perfect. It just needs a few homey touches.
家的气氛? 像什么?
Homey touches? Like what?
一扇门? 好吧 绅士晚安
A door? Well, gentlemen, I bid thee good night.
睡前我跟你讲个故事吧 我会讲
You want me to read you a bedtime story? I will.
我说晚安!
I said goodnight!
史瑞克 你在做什么?
Shrek, what are you doing?
我只是你知道哦 别担心
I just You know Oh, come on.
我只是开玩笑的
I was just kidding.
呃 那个 那是斯洛白克
And, uh, that one, that's Throwback,
是唯一一个吐过三个麦地的妖怪
the only ogre to ever spit over three wheatfields.
对 好
Right. Yeah.
哎 你能看星象说出我的未来吗?
Hey, can you tell my future from these stars?
星象不能告诉我们未来 它们告诉我们故事
The stars don't tell the future, Donkey. They tell stories.
看 布拉纳特臭气
Look, there's Bloodnut, the Flatulent.
- 你可以猜出为什么它很出名 - 你在编造
- You can guess what he's famous for. - I know you're making this up.
不 看 它在那里
No, look. There he is,
猎人都被它臭跑了
and there's the group of hunters running away from his stench.
它们只是一群小星星
That ain't nothin' but a bunch of little dots.
有时候事情不像表面上看起来那么简单
Sometimes things are more than they appear.
呃?
Hmm?
算了吧
Forget it.
哎 史瑞克 回到沼泽地之后我们做什么?
Hey, Shrek, what we gonna do when we get our swamp anyway?
我们的沼泽地?
Our swamp?
你知道 我们救了公主
You know, when we're through rescuing the princess.
我们? 驴子不是我们 没有我们
We? Donkey, there's no we. There's no our.
那是我的沼泽地
There's just me and my swamp.
我要做的第一件事就是在我的领土建一个十英尺高的围墙
The first thing I'm gonna do is build a ten-foot wall around my land.
你伤害了我 史瑞克
You cut me deep, Shrek.
你刚才深深的伤害了我
You cut me real deep just now.
你知道我在想什么吗?
You know what I think?
我想围墙只是为了堵人
I think this whole wall thing is just a way to keep somebody out.
- 不 你怎么想? - 你在隐瞒什么吗?
- No, doya think? - Are you hidin' something?
别介意 驴子
Never mind, Donkey.
哦 这是另一个洋葱的问题 不是吗?
Oh, this is another one of those onion things, isn't it?
不 这是一个不该谈的事情
No, this is one of those drop it and leave it alone things.
- 为什么你不想说这个? - 为什么你想?
- Why don't you want to talk about it? - Why do you want to?
- 为什么你要封闭你自己? - 我没有
- Why are you blocking? - I'm not blocking.
- 哦 是的 你有 - 驴子我警告你
- Oh, yes, you are. - Donkey, I'm warning you.
- 你想堵住谁? - 所有人! 行了吧?
- Who you trying to keep out? - Everyone! Okay?
哦 我们现在有所进展了
Oh, now we're gettin' somewhere.
哦 看在圣彼得的面上
Oh! For the love of Pete!
你的问题是什么? 你对世界有什么不满吗?
What's your problem? What you got against the whole world?
不是我有什么不满 知道吗?
I'm not the one with the problem, okay?
是世界遗弃了我
It's the world that seems to have a problem with me.
人们看见我就会说:啊救命 快跑
People take one look at me and go, Aah! Help! Run!
一个愚蠢而又丑陋的怪物
A big, stupid, ugly ogre!
他们不了解我就下了结论
They judge me before they even know me.
这就是为什么我最好离开
That's why I'm better off alone.
你知道什么?
You know what?
当我们见面是 我不认为你是一个愚蠢而又丑陋的怪物
When we met, I didn't think you was just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
那 呃 天上有驴子吗?
So, uh, are there any donkeys up there?
是的 那里有 是个多嘴
Well, there's, um, Gabby,
麻烦的小驴子
the Small and Annoying.
好的 我现在看到了 那个大的闪闪发光的 就在那里 那里的那个吗?
Okay, I see it now. The big shiny one, right there. That one there?
- 那是月亮 - 哦 是的
- That's the moon. - Oh, okay.
再让我看看
Again. Show me again.
镜子 镜子 让我再看看她 让我看到公主
Mirror, mirror, show her to me. Show me the princess.
哼
Hmph.
啊十全十美
Ah. Perfect.
嗯 你知道 我喜欢这样
Mmm, yeah, you know I like it like that.
- 对 宝贝 我说过我喜欢这样 - 驴子醒醒
- Come on, baby. I said I like it. - Donkey, wake up.
- 呃 什么? - 起来了
- Huh? What? - Wake up.
- 什么? - 早上好
- What? - Good morning.
你喜欢吃什么样的蛋?
How do you like your eggs?
- 早安 公主! - 这是怎么回事?
- Good morning, Princess! - What's all this about?
昨天我们一开始相处得有点不太好
We kind of got off to a bad start yesterday.
我想补偿你一下
I wanted to make it up to you.
毕竟 是你救了我
After all, you did rescue me.
Uh 谢谢了
Uh, thanks.
Well 快点吃 我们还有大段路在前头呢
Well, eat up. We've got a big day ahead of us.
史瑞克!
Shrek!
什么啊? 这是个赞美
What? It's a compliment.
我总是说"不吐不快"的
Better out than in, I always say.
Well 在公主面前可不该这样失态的
Well, it's no way to behave in front of a princess.
- 谢谢 - 她和你一样粗鲁
- Thanks. - She's as nasty as you are.
你知道吗? 你确实和我想象中的不太一样
You know, you're not exactly what I expected.
Well 也许在你了解了一个人 之前是不该对他乱下结论的
Well. Maybe you shouldn't judge people before you get to know them.
La liberte! Hey! (法语: 自由万岁!)
La liberte! "Hey!"
公主!
Princess!
你要干什么?
What are you doing?
安静些 mon cherie(法: 亲爱的) 因为我是你的救星!
Be still, "mon cherie," for I am your saviour!
我正救你离开这头绿色的...
And I am rescuing you from this green
- ...怪兽 - Hey!
- beast. - Hey!
那是我的公主! 去找你自己的吧!
That's my princess! Go find your own!
拜托 怪物! 你没看见我现在很忙吗?
Please, monster! Can't you see I'm a little busy here?
听着 老友 我不知道你认为自己是谁!
Look, pal, I don't know who you think you are!
Oh! 当然! Oh 真是失礼了!
Oh! Of course! Oh, how rude.
请允许我来自我介绍一下
Please let me introduce myseIf.
Oh 手足们!
Oh, Merry Men!
Ta, dah, dah, dah, whoo
I steal from the rich and give to the needy
- He takes a wee percentage - But I'm not greedy
I rescue pretty dam sels Man, I'm good
- What a guy, Monsieur Hood - Break it down
I like an honest fight and a saucy little maid
- What he's basically saying is he likes to get... - Paid
- So - When an ogre in the bush grabs a lady by the tush
- That's bad - That's bad
When a beauty's with a beast it makes me awfully mad
He's mad He's really, really mad
I'll take my blade and ram it through your heart
Keep your eyes on me, boys 'cause I'm about to start
伙计 这帮人渣可真讨厌!
Man, that was annoying!
Oh 你这个小...
Oh, you little...
Um 可以走了吗
Um, shall we?
保持联系
Hold the phone.
Oh! Whoa whoa whoa 等我一下
Oh! Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on now.
- 你从哪学来的? - 学什么?
- Where did that come from? - What?
那个啊! 刚才那里 真令人吃惊!
That! Back there. That was amazing!
你从哪学到的啊?
Where did you learn that?
Well 当你独自生活时
Well... When one lives alone,
uh 你必须得学点本领以防万一...
uh, one has to learn these things in case there's a...
- 你屁股上有支箭! - 什么?
- There's an arrow in your butt! - What?
- Oh 你能帮忙看看吗? - Oh no 这都是我的错
- Oh, would you look at that? - Oh, no. This is all my fault.
- 真的很对不起 - 为什么? 出什么事了?
- I'm so sorry. - Why? What's wrong?
- 史瑞克受伤了 - 史瑞克受伤了 史瑞克受伤了? Oh no Shrek你可千万别死啊!
- Shrek's hurt. - Shrek's hurt. Shrek's hurt? Oh, no, Shrek's gonna die.
- 驴子 我没事 - 你不可以这样子对我 我还年轻 你别死啊!
- Donkey, I'm okay. - You can't do this to me. I'm too young for you to die.
快抬起你的腿 转动你的头 大力咳两声
Keep your legs elevated. Turn your head and cough.
- 有谁会Heimlich急救法啊? - 驴子! 冷静点
- Does anyone know the Heimlich? - Donkey! Calm down.
如果你想帮Shrek 就到树林里去找有红色刺的蓝色花
If you want to help Shrek, run into the woods and find me a blue flower with red thorns.
蓝色花、红色刺 Okay 我马上去 蓝色花、红色刺 蓝色花、红色刺
Blue flower, red thorns. Okay, I'm on it. Blue flower, red thorns.
不要死 Shrek 如果你见到长隧道出现 千万别走进光里面!
Don't die, Shrek. If you see a long tunnel, stay away from the light!
- 驴子! - Oh yeah 好的 蓝色花、红色刺...
- Donkey! - Oh, yeah. Right. Blue flower, red thorns.
- 蓝色花、红色刺 - 那种花是用来干什么的?
- "Blue flower, red thorns." - What are the flowers for?
- 用来支开驴子的 - Ah
- For getting rid of Donkey. - Ah.
现在你不要动 我帮你把箭拔出来
Now you hold still, and I'll yank this thing out.
Ow! Hey! 别这么大力拔
Ow! Hey! Easy with the yankin'.
- 对不起 但是一定得拔出来的 - No 温柔点
- I'm sorry, but it has to come out. - No, it's tender.
现在继续吧
Now, hold on.
- 你这样做只会越帮越忙的 - 别动啊!
- What you're doing is the opposite of help. - Don't move.
- 听着 先暂停 - 你能不...
- Look, time out. - Would you...
Okay 那你说我们该怎样来?
Okay. What do you propose we do?
蓝色花、红色刺 蓝色花、红色刺...
Blue flower, red thorns. Blue flower, red thorns. Blue flower, red thorns.
这本来是很简单的事 如果我不是色盲的话!
This would be so much easier if I wasn't colour-blind!
- 蓝色花、红色刺 - Ow!
- Blue flower, red thorns. - Ow!
坚持住史瑞克! 我来了!
HoId on, Shrek! I'm comin'!
Ow! 受不了啦
Ow! Not good.
Okay Okay 我差不多能看见箭头了
Okay. Okay, I can nearly see the head.
- 这只是时... - Ow! Ohh!
- It's just about... - Ow! Ohh!
Ahem
Ahem.
什么也没发生 我们只是要 uh...
Nothing happened. We were just, uh...
听着 如果你们想单独相处的话 只需要开句声就行了 Okay?
Look, if you wanted to be alone, all you had to do was ask,Okay?
Oh 拜托! 那是我最不想干的事情
Oh, come on! That's the last thing on my mind.
公主只不过是要...Ugh!
The princess here was just... Ugh!
- Ow! - Hey 那是什么?
- Ow! - Hey, what's that?
那是...那是血吗?
That's... Is that blood?
My beloved monster and me
We go everywhere together
Wearin' a raincoat that has four sleeves
- Gets us through all kinds of weather - Aah!
She will always be the only thing
That comes between me and the awful sting
That comes from living in a world that's so damn mean
Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
Hey!
La-la, la-la, la-la-la-la
La-la, la-la, la-la
在这里 公主
There it is, Princess.
你的未来在等你
Your future awaits you.
- 那是杜洛克吗? - 是的 我知道
- That's DuLoc? - Yeah, I know.
你知道 史瑞克认为弗瓜王在弥补什么
You know, Shrek thinks Lord Farquaad's compensating for something,
我想说的是他有一个 哦
which I think means he has a really Ow!
呃 我 呃
Um, I, uh
- 我猜我们最好上路吧 - 好的
- I guess we better move on. - Sure.
但是 史瑞克?
But, Shrek?
我 我很担心驴子
I'm I'm worried about Donkey.
- 什么? - 我说 你看他
- What? - I mean, look at him.
- 他看起来很不好 - 你在说什么? 我很好
- He doesn't look so good. - What are you talking about? I'm fine.
他们总是这么说 然后他们就倒下了
That's what they always say, and then next thing you know, you're on your back.
- 死去 - 你知道 她是对的
- Dead. - You know, she's right.
你看起来气色不好 你想坐下休息一会吗?
You look awful. Do you want to sit down?
- 给你来点茶 - 我原来不想说
- I'll make you some tea. - I didn't want to say nothin',
我的脖子很疼 而且我要是像这样转头 瞧
but I got this twinge in my neck, and when I turn my head like this, look.
哦! 看见了?
Ow! See?
- 谁饿了吗? 我要去找点吃的 - 我去找材火
- Who's hungry? I'll find us some dinner. -I'll get the firewood.
你去哪里? 伙计 我的脚趾失去感觉了!
Hey, where you goin'? Oh, man, I can't feel my toes!
我没有感觉了!
I don't have any toes!
我想我需要一个拥抱
I think I need a hug.
嗯
Mmm.
嗯 很好吃 真的
Mmm. This is good. This is really good.
- 这是什么? - 草老鼠
- What is this? - Uh, weedrat.
是烧烤的
Rotisserie style.
别开玩笑了
No kidding.
真的 很美味
Well, this is delicious.
炖着吃也很香
Well, they're also great in stews.
我不是吹牛 我做的炖草老鼠一流
Now, I don't mean to brag, but I make a mean weedrat stew.
我想明天的晚餐应该会有点不同吧
I guess I'll bedining a little differently tomorrow night.
也许 你可以来沼泽看我
Maybe you can come visit me in the swamp sometime.
我会做各种美味给你
I'll cook all kinds of stuff for you.
沼泽蛤蟆汤 生鱼眼饼 你就说吧
Swamp toad soup, fish eye tartare you name it.
我想我会喜欢的
I'd like that.
呃 公主?
Um, Princess?
是的 史瑞克
Yes, Shrek?
我 我想
I, um, I was wondering.
你
Are you
你吃吗?
Are you gonna eat that?
- 伙计 很浪漫 不是吗? 看日出 - 日出?
- Man, isn't this romantic? Just look at that sunset. - Sunset?
哦 不! 我是说 太晚了
Oh, no! I mean, it's late.
- 太 太晚了 - 什么?
- I-It's very late. - What?
等一下 我明白是怎么回事了
Wait a minute. I see what's goin' on here.
- 你害怕黑夜 是吗? - 是的!
- You're afraid of the dark, aren't you? - Yes!
是的 是这样 我怕 你知道 我最好进去
Yes, that's it. I'm terrified. You know, I'd better go inside.
没什么 公主 我以前也怕黑
Don't feel bad, Princess. I used to be afraid of the dark, too, until
不 等等 我还是怕黑
Hey, no, wait. I'm still afraid of the dark.
晚安
Good night.
哦!
Ohh!
现在我知道发生了什么
Now I really see what's goin' on here.
你知道什么?
Oh, what are you talkin' about?
我什么也没有听见 但是我是动物 我有直觉
I don't even wanna hear it. Look, I'm an animal, and I got instincts.
我知道 你们互相爱慕对方 我能感觉的到
I know you two were diggin' on each other. I could feel it.
你疯了 我只是把她带给弗瓜王
You're crazy. I'm just bringing her back to Farquaad.
别 史瑞克 清醒点吧
Oh, come on, Shrek. Wake up and smell the pheromones.
- 没什么好说的 告诉她你的感觉 - 我
- Just go on in and tell her how you feel. - I
没什么好说的 还有 即使我要跟她去说
There's nothing to tell. Besides, even if I did tell her that,
你知道
well, you know
我还是不会去的 因为
and I'm not sayin' I do 'cause I don't
她是一位公主 而我是
she's a princess, and I'm
一个妖怪?
An ogre?
是的 一个妖怪
Yeah. An ogre.
- 你去哪里? - 去找些柴火
- Hey, where you goin'? - To get... more firewood.
公主?
Princess?
菲奥娜公主吗?
Princess Fiona?
公主 你在哪里?
Princess, where are you?
公主?
Princess?
这里不好玩 我不是在玩游戏
It's very spooky in here. I ain't playing no games.
- 啊! - 哦 不! - 不 救命!
- Aah! - Oh, no! - No, help!
- 嘘! - 史瑞克 史瑞克 史瑞克 - 不 没什么事了 没事了
- Shh! - Shrek! Shrek! Shrek! - No, it's okay. It's okay.
- 公主在哪里? - 驴子我就事公主
- What did you do with the princess? - Donkey, I'm the princess.
- 啊! - 是我 在这个身体里
- Aah! - It's me, in this body.
哦 我的上帝! 你吃了公主
Oh, my God! You ate the princess!
- 你能听到我吗? - 驴子!
- Can you hear me? - Donkey!
- 听着 保持呼吸! 我会把你弄出来的 - 不!
- Listen, keep breathing! I'll get you out of there! - No!
- 史瑞克 史瑞克 史瑞克 - 嘘
- Shrek! Shrek! Shrek! - Shh.
- 史瑞克 - 是我
- Shrek! - This is me.
公主?
Princess?
发生什么事了? 你怎么
What happened to you? You're, uh, uh,
变样了
uh, different.
- 我变丑了 对吧? - 哦 是的
- I'm ugly, okay? - Well, yeah!
是因为你吃的东西吗? 我知道不该吃那些东西
Was it something you ate? 'Cause I told Shrek those rats was a bad idea.
- 我说是因为你吃的东西 - 不
- You are what you eat, I said. Now - No.
我 我从记事起就这个样了
I I've been this way as long as I can remember.
你什么意思?我从未见过你这个样子
What do you mean? Look, I ain't never seen you like this before.
日落后才会这样
It only happens when the sun goes down.
白天一个样 晚上一个样
By night one way, by day another.
这是一个规律
This shall be the norm...
知道得到真爱人的吻
untiI you find true love's first kiss...
然后变成他的模样
and then take love's true form.
啊真美 我还不知道你会写诗
Ah, that's beautiful. I didn't know you wrote poetry.
这是诅咒
It's a spell.
我小的时候
When I was a little girl,
一个巫婆诅咒了我
a witch cast a spell on me.
每天晚上我就会变成这个样
Every night I become this.
一个可怕而又丑陋的怪兽
This horrible, ugly beast!
我被放进一间高塔 等待真爱来救我
I was placed in a tower to await the day my true love would rescue me.
这就是为什么明天日落前要跟弗瓜王结婚
That's why I have to marry Lord Farquaad tomorrow...
在他见到我以前
before the sun sets and he sees me...
像这样
like this.
好的 好的 镇静 看 这一点也不坏
All right, all right. Calm down. Look, it's not that bad.
我不会撒谎 你是丑 但不会太丑
You're not that ugly. Well, I ain't gonna lie. You are ugly.
你只是夜晚丑 但是史瑞克却时刻如此
But you only look like this at night. Shrek's ugly 24-7.
但是 驴子我是一位公主
But, Donkey, I'm a princess,
这不是一位公主该有的长相
and this is not how a princess is meant to look.
公主 你不跟弗瓜王结婚怎么样?
Princess, how 'bout if you don't marry Farquaad?
我必须
I have to.
只有真爱的人的吻才能解除咒语
Only my true love's kiss can break the spell.
但是 你是一个善良的怪兽
But, you know, um, you're kind of an ogre,
而且 史瑞克 你们有很多共同点
and Shrek well, you got a lot in common.
史瑞克?
Shrek?
公主 我首先 你好吗?
Princess, I Uh, how's it going, first of all?
好?我很好
Good? Um, good for me too.
我很好
I'm okay.
我看到这些花想到你 因为花很漂亮
I saw this flower and thought of you because it's pretty and
我不怎么喜欢 但是我想你会喜欢 因为你很漂亮
well, I don't really like it, but I thought you might like it 'cause you're pretty.
但是我仍然很喜欢 我
But I like you anyway. I'd uh, uh
我遇到麻烦了 好的 我们走吧
I'm in trouble. Okay, here we go.
我不能随便嫁人的
I can't just marry whoever I want.
看着我 驴子
Take a good look at me, Donkey.
我是说 真的
I mean, really,
谁会爱上一个丑八怪?
who could ever love a beast so hideous and ugly?
公主和丑八怪不能在一起
Princessand ugly don't go together.
这就是为什么我不能跟史瑞克在一起
That's why I can't stay here with Shrek.
我唯一的机会就是跟我真爱的人结婚
My only chance to live happily ever after is to marry my true love.
你不明白吗 驴子?
Don't you see, Donkey?
我必须这么做
That's just how it has to be.
这是解除咒语的唯一办法
It's the only way to break the spell.
- 你至少告诉史瑞克真相吧 - 不!
- You at least gotta tell Shrek the truth. - No!
你不能说一个字 没有人知道这个秘密
You can't breathe a word. No one must ever know.
如果要保密为什么要告诉我?
What's the point of being able to talk if you gotta keep secrets?
答应我不说 发誓
Promise you won't tell. Promise!
好的 好的 我不会告诉他 但是你可以说
All right, all right. I won't tell him. But you should.
我知道在此结束之前 我需要接受治疗
I just know before this is over, I'm gonna need a whole lot of serious the rapy.
瞧 我的眼睛在抽搐
Look at my eye twitchin'.
告诉他 不告诉他
I tell him, I tell him not.
告诉他
I tell him.
史瑞克!
Shrek!
史瑞克 有些事 我想
Shrek, there's something I want
史瑞克
Shrek.
- 你还好吧? - 非常好!
- Are you all right? - Perfect!
空前良好
Never been better.
我 我不有些事情我要告诉你
I I don't There's something I have to tell you.
你不用告诉我任何事情 公主
You don't have to tell me anything, Princess.
- 我昨晚听的够多的了 什么 - 你听见我的谈话了?
- I heard enough last night. - You heard what I said?
每一个字
Every word.
我想你能理解
I thought you'd understand.
我理解
Oh, I understand.
就像你说的 谁会爱上一个丑八怪?
Like you said, Who could love a hideous, ugly beast?
但是我以为这对你不重要
But I thought that wouldn't matter toyou.
是吗? 重要
Yeah? Well, it does.
准时到达
Ah, right on time.
公主 我给你带来个小玩意
Princess, I've brought you a little something.
我错过了什么吗? 我错过了什么吗?
What'd I miss? What'd I miss?
是谁说的? 不可能事驴子
Who said that? Couldn't have been a donkey.
公主
Princess Fiona.
按照承诺 给我地契
As promised. Now hand it over.
好的 妖怪 你沼泽地的地契已经写好了
Very well, ogre. The deed to your swamp, cleared out, asagreed.
在我改变主意之前拿走吧
Take it and go before I change my mind.
原谅我 公主 让你吃惊了
Forgiveme, Princess, for startling you,
但是你也让我吃惊了
but you startled me,
我从没有见过这么耀眼的美丽
for I have never seen such a radiant beauty before.
我是弗瓜王
I am Lord Farquaad.
弗瓜王? 哦 不 不 不
Lord Farquaad? Oh, no, no.
原谅我 王 我正要
Forgive me, my lord, for I was just saying...
简短的告别
a short... farewell.
真善良 你不必对那个妖怪那么客气
That is so sweet. You don't have to waste good manners on the ogre.
它不懂什么是感情
It's not like it has feelings.
你是对的 它不懂
No, you're right. It doesn't.
公主 美丽 洁白无暇的公主
Princess Fiona, beautiful, fair, flawless Fiona.
我向你求婚
I ask your hand in marriage.
你愿意做我的新娘吗?
Will you be the perfect bride for the perfect groom?
王 我愿意 没有什么
Lord Farquaad, I accept. Nothing would make
我来计划 我们明天就举行婚礼!
Excellent! I'll start the plans, for tomorrow we wed!
不 我是说
No! I mean, uh,
为什么要等?
why wait?
让我们在今天日落以前就结婚
Let's get married today before the sun sets.
哦 着急了 是吧? 你是对的
Oh, anxious, are we? You're right.
越快越好 有很多事情要做
The sooner, the better. There's so much to do!
酒宴 乐队 客人名单
There's the caterer, the cake, the band, the guest list.
队长 列出客人名单!
Captain, round up some guests!
再见 妖怪
Fare-thee-well, ogre.
史瑞克 你在干什么? 是你让她走得
Shrek, what are you doing? You're letting her get away.
- 是吗? 那又怎么样呢? - 史瑞克 有些事你应该知道
- Yeah? So what? - Shrek, there's something about her you don't know.
我昨晚跟她谈了一夜 她是
Look, I talked to her last night. She's
我知道你跟她昨晚谈了一夜 你们事好朋友 不是吗?
I know you talked to her last night. You're great pals, aren'tya?
如果你们那么要好 你为什么不跟着她走?
Now, if you two are such good friends, why don't you follow her home?
史瑞克 我想跟着你
Shrek, I I wanna go with you.
我告诉过你 你不能跟我回家 我没有说过吗?
I told you, didn't I? You're not coming home with me.
我要一个人! 我的沼泽! 我的! 没有其它人!
I live alone! My swamp! Me! Nobody else!
明白吗? 没有其它人!
Understand? Nobody!
特别不要无用 可怜 烦人的和会说话的驴子
Especially useless, pathetic, annoying, talking donkeys!
- 但是 我想知道 - 你想知道什么?
- But I thought - Yeah. You know what?
你的想法错了
You thought wrong!
史瑞克
Shrek.
我听见一个秘密
I heard there was asecret chord
是戴维说的 来让王高兴
That David played and it pleased the Lord
但是你不是真正想要音乐
But you don't really care formusic, doya
就像第四 第五
I tgoes like this the fourth, the fifth
镜子倒下 主人离开
The minor fall the major lift
困惑的国王
The baffled king composing hallelujah
Hallelujah
亲爱的 我很早就在那里
Baby, I'v been here before
我知道我走过的每一个房间
I know this room I've walked this floor
我过去常常一个人住在认识你之前
I used to live a lone before I knew you
我看到你的旗帜
I've seen your flag on the marblearch
但是爱情不是胜利的标志
But love is not a victory march
他是冷酷的和毁灭的
It's a cold and it's a broken hallelujah
Hallelujah
我在爱情学会的东西
And all lever learned from love
就是如何射中别人
Is how to shoot at someone
射中青睐你的人
Who out drew you
这就是你今晚听到的喊叫
And it's not a cry you can hear at night
是见不了光的某个人
It's not somebody who's seen the light
他是残酷的和毁灭的
It's a cold and it's a broken hallelujah
Hallelujah
驴子?
Donkey?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我想 对每一个人 你要学会认识墙
I would think, of all people, you would recognize a wall when you see one.
对
Well, yeah.
但是墙应该围绕着我的沼泽 而不是穿过
But the wall's supposed to go around my swamp, not through it.
是这样的 这是你的一半 那是我的一半
It is around your half. See, that's your half, and this is my half.
哦 你的一半
Oh! Your half. Hmm.
对 我的一半 我帮助你救了公主
Yes, my half. I helped rescue the princess.
我做了一半的工作 我应该得到一半的战利品
I did half the work, I get half the booty.
现在把那个大石头给我 就是像你脑袋的那个
Now hand me that big old rock, the one that looks like your head.
- 退后! - 不 你后退
- Back off! - No, you back off.
- 这是我的沼泽 - 我的
- This is my swamp! - Our swamp.
- 松手 驴子! - 不 你松
- Let go, Donkey! - You let go.
- 蠢驴子! - 臭妖怪!
- Stubborn jack ass! - Smelly ogre.
好吧!
Fine!
- 回来 我还没有说完 - 但是我已经跟你说完了
- Hey, come back here. I'm not through with you yet. - Well, I'm through with you.
跟你在一起 你总是 我 我 我
Uh-uh. You know, with you it's always, Me, me, me!
猜是什么! 该我了!
Well, guess what! Now it's my turn!
闭上嘴 听我说!
So you just shut up and pay attention!
你对我总是很刻薄
You are mean to me.
你侮辱我而且我做的事你不领情
You insult me and you don't appreciate anything that I do!
你总是把我推来推去
You're always pushing me around or pushing me away.
是吗 如果我对你这么坏 你为什么还要会来?
Oh, yeah? Well, if I treated you so bad, how come you came back?
因为我们是朋友 朋友是会原谅彼此的
Because that's what friends do! They forgive each other!
也许你是对的 驴子
Oh, yeah. You're right, Donkey.
我原谅你背叛了我
I forgive you... for stabbin' me in the back!
你把自己包裹了好几层 你害怕你自己的感觉
Ohh! You're so wrapped up in layers, onion boy, you're afraid of your own feelings.
- 走开! - 你又那么做了
- Go away! - There you are, doing it again just like you did to Fiona.
就像对公主一样 她喜欢你 也许是爱你
All she ever do was like you, maybe even love you.
爱我? 她说我是一个丑八怪
Love me? She said I was ugly, a hideouscreature.
我听见你们两个的谈话了
I heard the two of you talking.
她不是说你
She wasn't talkin' about you.
她不是说你 还有别人
She was talkin' about, uh, somebody else.
她不是说我?
She wasn't talking about me?
那她说的是谁?
Well, then who was she talking about?
我不会说一个字 反正你也没有兴趣听
Uh-uh, no way. I ain't saying anything. You don't wanna listen to me.
- 真的吗? 真的吗? - 驴子!
- Right? Right? - Donkey!
- 不! - 好吧
- No! - Okay, look.
抱歉 还好吗?
I'm sorry, all right?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
好吧 我是一个愚蠢而又丑陋的妖怪
I guess I am just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
你能原谅我吗?
Can you forgive me?
这就是作为朋友应该的 对吗?
Hey, that's what friends are for, right?
正确 朋友?
Right. Friends?
朋友
Friends.
这样啊
So, um,
公主是怎么说我的
what did Fiona say about me?
你为什么问我 你应该去问她
What are you asking me for? Why don't you just go ask her?
婚礼!我们别错过这个
The wedding! We'll never make it in time.
别急 有志者事竟成
Ha-ha-ha! Never fear, for where there's a will, there's a way,
我有办法
and I have a way.
驴子?
Donkey?
我猜这是我动物的魅力
I guess it's just my animal magnetism.
你 过来
Aw, come here, you.
别这样 没有人喜欢拍驴子屁的
All right, all right. Don't get all slobbery. No one likes a kiss ass.
好 上来 抓紧
All right, hop on and hold on tight.
还没来得及寄安全带
I haven't had a chance to install the seat bets yet.
呜
Whoo!
杜洛克的人们
People of DuLoc,
我们今天到这来
we gather here today...
来见证
to bearwitness...
- 我们王国的联合 - 呃
- to the union... - Um
- 为我们的新国王 - 打扰一下
- of our new king - Excuse me.
我们能不能跳到我愿意?
Could we just skip ahead to the I do's?
继续
Go on.
走吧 高兴点 需要你时我会吹口哨的
Go ahead, have some fun. If we need you, I'll whistle. How about that?
史瑞克 等等 等等!
Shrek, wait, wait! Wait a minute!
- 你要做那件事 对吗? - 你在说什么?
- You wanna do this right, don't you? - What are you talking about?
你在等待一句台词
There's a line you gotta wait for.
等待牧师说 现在说否则永远保持沉默
The preacher's gonna say, Speak now or forever hold your peace.
- 这时你说 我反对 - 我没有时间听你说
- That's when you say, I object! - I don't have time for this!
等等 你等我说完
Wait. What are you doing? Listen to me!
- 你爱那个女人吗? - 是的
- Look, you love this woman, don't you? - Yes.
- 你想牵她的手 对吗? - 是的
- You wanna hold her? - Yes.
- 让她高兴? - 是的
- Please her? - Yes!
那你就要去 去 尝试一种温柔
Then you got to, got to try a little tenderness
- 女人都喜欢这种浪漫! - 是的 完全正确
- The chicks love that romantic crap! - All right! Cut it out.
- 这家伙什么时候会说这个了? - 我们得查一下
- When does this guy say the line? - We gotta check it out.
以我的权力
And so, by the powervested in me,
- 你看见什么了? - 全城的人都在
- What do you see? - The whole town's in there.
- 我宣布你们为夫妻 - 他们在祭坛上
- I now pronounce you husband and wife, - They're at the altar.
- 国王和王后 - 他已经说了
- king and queen. - Mother Fletcher! He already said it.
看在圣彼得的面上
Oh, for the love of Pete!
我反对!
I object!
史瑞克?
Shrek?
现在他会做什么?
Oh, now what does he want?
大家 过得很愉快 是吗?
Hi, everyone. Havin' a good time, are ya?
我喜欢杜洛克 首先
I love DuLoc, first of all.
- 这里很干净 - 你来这里干什么?
- Very clean. - What are you doing here?
没有人想要你来参加婚礼
Really, it's rude enough being alive when no one wants you,
你来这里已经很无礼了公主
but showing up uninvited to a wedding
- 我想跟你谈谈 - 你想说什么?
- I need to talk toyou. - Oh, now you wanna talk?
有一点晚 但是如果你原谅我
It's a little late for that, so if you'll excuse me
但是你不能嫁给他 为什么呢?
- But you can't marry him. - And why not?
因为 因为他娶你只是为了当上国王
Because Because he's just marrying you so he can be king.
愤怒!公主 别听他的
Outrageous! Fiona, don't listen to him.
- 他不是你的真爱 - 你懂爱吗?
- He's not your true love. - And what do you know about true love?
嗯 我 我
Well, I Uh
- 我是说 - 这真是有意思
- I mean - Oh, this is precious.
妖怪爱上了公主
The ogre has fallen in love with the princess!
哦 神啊
Oh, good Lord
公主和妖怪
An ogre and a princess!
史瑞克 这是真的吗?
Shrek, is this true?
谁管呢?真有趣!
Who cares? It's preposterous!
公主 我的爱人 吻完后我们就能得到永远的幸福
Fiona, my love, we're but a kiss away from our happily ever after.
吻我!
Now kiss me! Mmmm!
白天一个样 晚上一个样
By night one way, by day another.
我想给你看我晚上的样子
I wanted to show you before.
哦
Well, uh,
这能解释一切
that explains a lot.
真恶心
Ugh! It's disgusting!
士兵 士兵
Guards! Guards!
我命令你们把他们赶走
l order you to get that out of my sight now! Get them!
- 把他们两个都赶走 - 不 不
- Get them both! - No, no!
这不会改变任何事情 这个婚姻任然有效 我任然是国王
This hocus-pocusalters nothing. This marriage is binding, and that make smeking!
- 瞧 瞧 - 不 放开我 史瑞克!
- See? See? - No, let go of me! Shrek!
- 不! - 别光站在那里 一群笨蛋
- No! - Don't just stand there, you morons.
躲开!公主!
Get out of my way! Fiona!
啊!
Arrgh!
我要让你后悔和我见面 我要让你受尽折磨
I'll make you regret the day we met. I'll see you drawn and quartered!
- 到时候你会求我杀了你 - 不 史瑞克!
- You'll beg for death to save you! - No! Shrek!
- 至于你 我的妻子 - 公主!
- And as for you, my wife, - Fiona!
我会把你锁到高塔中来渡过你的余生
I'll have you locked back in that tower for the rest of your days!
我是国王
I am king!
我有权命令 我至高无上 我至
I will have order! I will have perfection! I will have
啊!
Aaah!
- 啊! - 好吧 任何人别动
- Aah! - All right. Nobody move.
我有一条龙 而且会毫不犹豫的使用
I got a dragon here, and I'm not afraid to use it.
我是头发怒的驴子
I'm a donkey on the edge!
盛大的婚礼 他们不会持久 对吗?
Celebrity marriages. They never last, do they?
去把 史瑞克
Go ahead, Shrek.
呃 公主?
Uh, Fiona?
是的 史瑞克?
Yes, Shrek?
我 我爱你
I I love you.
真的吗?
Really?
真的 真的
Really, really.
我也爱你
I love you too.
啊!
Aawww!
直到你找到真爱并得到他的吻
Until you find true love's first kiss...
然后变成他的模样
and then take love's true form.
变成他的模样 变成他的模样
Take love's true form. Take love's true form.
公主?
Fiona?
公主
Fiona.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
是的 很好
Well, yes.
但我不明白
But I don't understand.
你应该更漂亮
I'm supposed to be beautiful.
你很漂亮
But you are beautiful.
我希望是一个幸福的结局
I was hoping this would be a happy ending.
我想爱情是神话故事中唯一真实的东西
I thought love was only true in fairy tales
哦!
Oy!
对别人有意义 但是对我没有
Meant for someone else but not for me
爱情不会光顾我
Love was out to get me
好像是这样
That's the way it seemed
失望袭击着我的梦想
Disappointment haunted all my dreams
但是当我看到她的脸
And then I saw her face
现在我是一个信徒
Now I'm a believer
不仅是个踪迹
And not a trace
从不怀疑
Of doubt in my mind
- 我恋爱了 - 哦 啊
- I'm in love - Ooh ahh
我是一个信徒 我离不开她
I'm a believer I couldn 't leaveher
如果我试了
If I tried
神会保佑我 保佑每一个人
God bless us, every one.
一起来吧 当我看见她的脸
Come on, y'all! Then I saw her face Ha-ha!
现在我是一个信徒 听!
Now I'm a believer Listen!
不是踪迹
Not a trace
从不怀疑
Of doubt in my mind
我恋爱了
I'm in love Ooh-ahh
我是个信徒
I'm a believer I couldn't leave her if I tried
- 哦 - 哦
- Ooh! - Uh!
当我看见她的脸
Then I saw her face
我是一个信徒
Now I'm a believer Hey!
不是踪迹
Not a trace Uhh! Yeah.
从不怀疑 再来一次
Of doubt in my mind One more time!
我恋爱了
I'm in love I'm a believer
大家一起来
Come on!
我相信 我相信 我相信 我相信
I believe, I believe I believe, I believe
我相信 我相信 我相信 我相信 我相信
I believe, I believe I believe, I believe, I believe, hey
跟我一起唱
Y' all sing it with me! I
相信
Believe
后面的人
I believe People in the back!
- 相信 - 我信
- I believe - I'm a believer
相信
I believe
我相信
哦 非常有趣
Oh, that's funny. Oh. Oh.
我不能呼吸 我不能呼吸了
I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
我相信自我感觉
I believe in self-assertion
命运有时会改变
Destiny or as light diversion
现在好像青睐我了
Now it seems I've got my head on straight
我是一个丑八怪 一个妖怪
I'm a freak an apparition
Seems I've made the right decision
To try to turn back now it might be too late
- I want to stay home today - Don't wanna go out
- If anyone comes to play - Gonna get thrown out
- I wanna stay home today - Don't want no company
No way
Yeah, yeah, yeah
I wanna be a millionaire some day
But know what it feels like to give it away
Watch memarch to the beat of my own drum
And it's off to the moon and then back again
Same old day Same situation
My happiness rears back as if to say
- I wanna stay home today - Don't wanna go out
- If anyone comes my way - Gonna get thrown out
- I wanna stay home today - Don't want no company
No way
Yeah, yeah, yeah
I wanna stay home stay home, stay home
- I wanna stay home today - Don't wanna go out
- If anyone comes to play - Gonna get thrown out
I wanna stay home today
Don't want no company No way
Yeah, yeah, yeah
I get such a thrill when you lookin my eyes
My heart skips a beat Girl, I feel so alive
Please tell me, baby if all this is true
'Cause deep down inside all I wanted was you
Oh-oh-oh Makes me wanna dance
Oh-oh-oh It's a new romance
Oh-oh-oh I look into your eyes
Oh-oh-oh The best years of our lives
When we first met I could hardly believe
The things that would happen and we could achieve
So let's be together for all of our time
Oh, girl, I'm so thankful that you are still mine
You always consider me like an ugly duckling
And treat me like a Nostradamus was why I had to get my shine on
I break a little something to keep my mind on
'Cause you had my mind gone Eh-eh, eh-eh, eh-eh
Turn the lights on, Come on, baby Let's just rewind the song
'Cause all I want to do is make the rest years the best years
All night long
- Oh-oh-oh, makes me wanna dance - Makes me wanna dance
- Oh-oh-oh, it's a new romance - It's a new romance
- Oh-oh-oh, I look into your eyes - Oh, yeah, yeah
- Look into your eyes - Oh-oh-oh
- The best years of our lives - Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
- Oh-oh-oh, makes me wanna dance - Whoa-oh-oh, dance, yeah
Oh-oh-oh It's a new romance
- Oh-oh-oh, I look into your eyes - Look into your eyes, yeah
Oh-oh-oh The best years of our lives
Everything looks bright
Standing in your light
Everything feels right
What's left is out of sight
What's a girl to do I'm telling you You're on my mind
I wanna be with you
'Cause when you're standin'next to me
It's like wow
And all your kisses seem to set me free
And when we touch it's such a rush I can't get enough
It's like It's like Ooh-ooh
Hey, what
It's like wow Ooh-ooh, hey
Hey, yeah It's like wow
Everything is looking right now, right now
- It's like wow - And I got this feeling
This feeling it's just like wow
It's just like wow
- You are all I'm thinking of. - Like wow
Everything feels right Everything feels right
- Like wow - Everything looks bright
All my senses are right.
- Like wow - Everything feels right
Baby, baby, baby the way I'm feeling you
Is like wow
There is something that I see
In the way you look at me
There's a smile There's a truth
In your eyes
What an unexpected way
On this unexpected day
Could it be
This is where I belong
It is you I have loved
All along
There's no more mystery
It is finallyclearto me
You're the home my heart's searched for
So long
It is you I have loved
Allalong
Whoa, over and over
I'm filled with emotion
As I look
Into your perfect face